<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gordon Wintrob's Personal Site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Gordon Wintrob's Personal Site]]></description><link>http://gwintrob.com/</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 15:27:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://gwintrob.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><author><![CDATA[Gordon Wintrob]]></author><item><title><![CDATA[Mayday! Mayday! Are airplanes getting more dangerous?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html><html><head><title>Mayday! Mayday! Are airplanes getting more dangerous?</title><meta name="description" content="Gordon Wintrob's Personal Site"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="http://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Raleway:100,400,600"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/style.css"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/ss-gizmo.css"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/ss-social-circle.css"><script>!function(){var analytics=window.analytics=window.analytics||[];if(!analytics.initialize)if(analytics.invoked)window.console&&console.error&&console.error("Segment snippet included twice.");else{analytics.invoked=!0;analytics.methods=["trackSubmit","trackClick","trackLink","trackForm","pageview","identify","group","track","ready","alias","page","once","off","on"];analytics.factory=function(t){return function(){var e=Array.prototype.slice.call(arguments);e.unshift(t);analytics.push(e);return analytics}};for(var t=0;t<analytics.methods.length;t++){var e=analytics.methods[t];analytics[e]=analytics.factory(e)}analytics.load=function(t){var e=document.createElement("script");e.type="text/javascript";e.async=!0;e.src=("https:"===document.location.protocol?"https://":"http://")+"cdn.segment.com/analytics.js/v1/"+t+"/analytics.min.js";var n=document.getElementsByTagName("script")[0];n.parentNode.insertBefore(e,n)};analytics.SNIPPET_VERSION="3.0.1";
analytics.load("Boo2cBGyhUD4L9UEaLSQXJr2MMZWP7tu");
analytics.page()
}}();</script><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/c3/0.4.8/c3.min.css"></head><body><div class="nav"><a href="/" class="a-fade ss-gizmo ss-home a-home"></a></div><div class="header"><h1 class="name">Gordon Wintrob</h1><div class="social-links"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">linkedin</a><a href="https://twitter.com/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">twitter</a><a href="https://github.com/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">octocat</a><a href="/rss.xml" class="a-fade ss-icon">rss</a><a href="mailto:gwintrob@gmail.com?Subject=Hey Gordon" class="a-fade ss-icon">mail</a></div></div><div class="article"><h1 class="article-title">Mayday! Mayday! Are airplanes getting more dangerous?</h1><div class="article-contents"><p>Modern airplane travel is spectacular.
The Department of Transportation <a href="http://www.rita.dot.gov/bts/press_releases/bts015_15">reported</a> that an all-time high 848 million passengers flew in the U.S. in 2014.
And remarkably, all of those passengers survived.</p>
<p>With recent tragedies like the missing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malaysia_Airlines_Flight_370">Malaysia Airlines flight</a> and <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2015/03/24/world/europe/germanwings-plane-crash-map.html">Germanwings crash</a>, I wondered if airplane crashes are changing.
Although technology lowers the incidence of crashes, perhaps the few remaining incidents are increasingly catastrophic.
As dangerous situations become less likely, do they also become more fatal?
To answer this question, I gathered statistics from the <a href="http://www.baaa-acro.com/presentation/">Bureau of Aircraft Accidents</a> and released the data on <a href="https://github.com/gwintrob/aircraft-incidents/">GitHub</a>.</p>
<p>Here&#39;s a look at some of the initial data for commercial flights.
Total aviation fatalities have been decreasing since 1976, especially in the US:</p>
<p><h2 class="center">Total Fatalities</h2></p>
<div id="chart-fatalities" class="chart"></div>

<p>This high level of safety is only possible with massive investments in safety and automation.
Thanks to more reliable engines and the latest autopilot systems, human error is the most common factor in airplane crashes.
My guess is that these errors make the remaining accidents more lethal.
Here&#39;s what I found about risk and safety in modern aviation.</p>
<h3 id="potential-autopilot-dangers">Potential Autopilot Dangers</h3>
<p>By 1980, when cockpit automation was pervasive, researchers began to consider potential negative effects of autopilot (e.g. <a href="http://www.ise.ncsu.edu/nsf_itr/794B/papers/Wiener_Curry_1980_Ergo.pdf">PDF link</a>).
Intuitively, autopilot creates additional challenges for pilots.
They can accidentally misconfigure the system, write off a legitimate problem as computer error, or incorrectly compensate beyond autopilot corrections.</p>
<p>Another potential challenge: if the vast majority of flight time is controlled via automation, then perhaps pilots have less experience handling real-world incidents.
A <a href="http://hfs.sagepub.com/content/56/8/1506">2014 paper</a> examines how well pilots retained manual flying skills in a flight simulator.
The researchers find some issues with remaining focused on flight tasks without autopilot.
Although advanced autopilot may reduce problems in the cockpit, it might make pilots less prepared and accidents more severe.</p>
<h3 id="analyzing-airplane-crashes">Analyzing Airplane Crashes</h3>
<p>To understand whether or not planes are getting more dangerous, I focused on catastrophic accidents when all of the passengers and crew perish.
I expected a higher percentage of catastrophic accidents over time due to the increased usage of autopilot.
The data shows mixed results:</p>
<p><h2 class="center">Accidents with no Survivors</h2></p>
<div id="chart-survivors" class="chart"></div>

<p>From 1976 to 2011, the percentage of accidents with no survivors fell to a low of 14%.
More recently, catastrophic incidents increased dramatically: nearly 45% of commercial accidents in 2014 had no survivors.
Catastrophic crashes like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indonesia_AirAsia_Flight_8501">AirAsia 8501</a>, make up 9 of the 20 incidents in the dataset from 2014.
The upwards trend supports my hypothesis that aircraft accidents are increasingly fatal, but the causes range from bad weather to a Boeing&nbsp;777 <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malaysia_Airlines_Flight_17">shot down over Ukraine</a>.
Ultimately, fatal incidents are so rare that it&#39;s difficult to draw a conclusion.</p>
<p>Accidents with no survivors tend to stick out in our minds, but I also wanted to consider the overall plane crash fatality rate.
This graph shows the ratio of fatalities to passengers onboard the aircraft:</p>
<p><h2 class="center">Accident Fatality Rate</h2></p>
<div id="chart-fatality-rate" class="chart"></div>

<p>After hitting a low of 9% in 1990, the fatality rate has hit record highs in the past two years.
In 2014, 79% of passengers involved in aircraft incidents perished.
Like catastrophic crashes, the overall fatality rate is clearly trending downwards and 2014 may have been an outlier year.</p>
<h3 id="aviation-safety-data">Aviation Safety Data</h3>
<p>Are airplanes getting more dangerous?
Absolutely not.
In 2014, there was one accident for every <a href="http://www.iii.org/fact-statistic/aviation">4.4 million flights</a>, the lowest rate in history.
This dataset shows that there might be a recent increase in accident fatality rate, but accidents are thankfully so rare that there&#39;s no clear trend.</p>
<p>Importantly, government organizations like the <a href="http://www.ntsb.gov/investigations/AccidentReports/Pages/aviation.aspx">FAA</a> and <a href="http://easa.europa.eu/newsroom-and-events/general-publications">EASA</a> generally release written reports on aviation incidents, rather than machine-readable data.
I encourage others to help standardize and analyze this data on <a href="https://github.com/gwintrob/aircraft-incidents">GitHub</a>.
Rigorously studying disasters makes everyone&#39;s lives safer.</p>
</div><div class="footer"><hr><small>Want to get in touch? <a href="https://twitter.com/gwintrob">Tweet</a> 
at me.</small></div></div><script type="text/javascript" src="http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.11.2/jquery.min.js"></script><script type="text/javascript" src="http://d3js.org/d3.v3.min.js"></script><script type="text/javascript" src="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/c3/0.4.8/c3.min.js"></script><script type="text/javascript" src="javascripts/aircraft_incidents.js"></script></body></html>]]></description><link>http://gwintrob.com/articles/mayday-mayday-are-airplanes-getting-more-dangerous</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://gwintrob.com/articles/mayday-mayday-are-airplanes-getting-more-dangerous</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Wintrob]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[7 Lessons for Language Learners]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html><html><head><title>7 Lessons for Language Learners</title><meta name="description" content="Gordon Wintrob's Personal Site"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="http://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Raleway:100,400,600"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/style.css"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/ss-gizmo.css"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/ss-social-circle.css"><script>!function(){var analytics=window.analytics=window.analytics||[];if(!analytics.initialize)if(analytics.invoked)window.console&&console.error&&console.error("Segment snippet included twice.");else{analytics.invoked=!0;analytics.methods=["trackSubmit","trackClick","trackLink","trackForm","pageview","identify","group","track","ready","alias","page","once","off","on"];analytics.factory=function(t){return function(){var e=Array.prototype.slice.call(arguments);e.unshift(t);analytics.push(e);return analytics}};for(var t=0;t<analytics.methods.length;t++){var e=analytics.methods[t];analytics[e]=analytics.factory(e)}analytics.load=function(t){var e=document.createElement("script");e.type="text/javascript";e.async=!0;e.src=("https:"===document.location.protocol?"https://":"http://")+"cdn.segment.com/analytics.js/v1/"+t+"/analytics.min.js";var n=document.getElementsByTagName("script")[0];n.parentNode.insertBefore(e,n)};analytics.SNIPPET_VERSION="3.0.1";
analytics.load("Boo2cBGyhUD4L9UEaLSQXJr2MMZWP7tu");
analytics.page()
}}();</script></head><body><div class="nav"><a href="/" class="a-fade ss-gizmo ss-home a-home"></a></div><div class="header"><h1 class="name">Gordon Wintrob</h1><div class="social-links"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">linkedin</a><a href="https://twitter.com/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">twitter</a><a href="https://github.com/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">octocat</a><a href="/rss.xml" class="a-fade ss-icon">rss</a><a href="mailto:gwintrob@gmail.com?Subject=Hey Gordon" class="a-fade ss-icon">mail</a></div></div><div class="article"><h1 class="article-title">7 Lessons for Language Learners</h1><div class="article-contents"><p>Learning a new language has many well-researched benefits.
This year, I&#39;ve set aside time to learn German and build more projects in public.
And this month, I&#39;m launching a new website that achieves both goals: <a href="https://noobgerman.com/">Noob German</a> (more on this later).</p>
<p>Here are seven scientifically-backed lessons to help learn a new language.</p>
<h3>
1. You&#39;re not too old
</h3>

<p>   Prevailing wisdom said that only children&#39;s flexible brains could learn a new language.
   As recently as <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1467-9922.2009.00507.x/abstract">2009</a>, researchers found that adult learners almost never attain fluency.</p>
<p>   <img src="images/old_dog.jpg" width="400px" class="block-center"></img></p>
<p>   Thankfully, if you&#39;re learning a language as an adult, you&#39;re not out of luck!
   A <a href="http://www.newscientist.com/article/mg21128224.000-age-no-excuse-for-failing-to-learn-a-new-language.html">2011 study</a> showed that adult learners were better at learning new grammar patterns.
   More recently, professors from <a href="http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032974">UIC and Georgetown</a> demonstrated that adults can retain this knowledge even after several months not speaking the language.</p>
<h3>
2. Plan a trip
</h3>

<p>  Duolingo sponsored an <a href="http://static.duolingo.com/s3/DuolingoReport_Final.pdf">independent report</a> to measure their app&#39;s effectiveness.
  The app is incredibly valuable: 26-49 hours of Duolingo practice works as well as a first college semester Spanish course.</p>
<p>  The study quantifies how the reason for learning a new language affects success.
  Studying for personal interest shows the worst improvement for each hour of study despite being the most common motivator.
  The most effective motivator? Studying for travel.
  Students motivated by a trip learn more than three times as much per hour of study.</p>
<p>  <img src="images/travel.jpg" width="600px" class="block-center"></img></p>
<p>  If you&#39;re looking to learn a language, nothing lights a fire in your belly like an upcoming trip to Oktoberfest or Carnival.</p>
<h3>
3. Chinese characters vs. English words
</h3>

<p>   English speakers learning Chinese or another <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logogram">logographic</a> language need a lot of patience.
   Even native speakers acquire these languages differently.</p>
<p>   For example, a study of education systems published in 1992 (<a href="http://www.cogsci.ucsd.edu/~deak/classes/EDS115/Stevenson_Stigler_1992.pdf">PDF link</a>) considers how grade school learners read above their grade level.
   They find that more students in Beijing enter first grade above expected reading levels compared to students in Chicago.
   But, the percentage of Beijing students reading above grade level quickly falls to 0, while many Chicago students continue outperforming:</p>
<p>   <img src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1AcRcmuslso6jcLUhUYIZd18tcYTbo86Dxyzo1jjOS1w/pubchart?oid=568842167&amp;format=image" alt="Ability to read above grade level"></p>
<p>   This makes sense: logographic languages don&#39;t have words that can be decoded into familiar parts.
   If you&#39;re learning an alphabetic language like English or German, you can infer vocab from simpler words.
   For example, knowing &quot;birth&quot; (&quot;Geburt&quot;) and &quot;day&quot; (&quot;Tag&quot;) means you&#39;ve already learned &quot;birthday&quot; (&quot;Geburtstag&quot;).
   Logographic language learners don&#39;t have these helpful cues.</p>
<h3>
4. Speaking is fundamental
</h3>

<p>   Depending on your goals, learning to speak a language generally reaps more tangible results than learning to read.
   It doesn&#39;t matter how many words you can read on the menu if you just want to order dinner!
   Studies on poor readers across languages prove this point.</p>
<p>   The <a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/10888438.2012.689787#.VOIrm7DF84Q">latest research</a> shows that ineffective foreign language readers have two main problems.
   First, they lack <strong>morphological awareness</strong>, the ability to identify word parts that are significant (like the Chicago grade schoolers decoding new vocab).
   Second, they underperform in <strong>phonological awareness</strong>, hearing the sounds that make up words.</p>
<p>   Diligently studying words&#39; components and sounds can accelerate learning.
   Importantly, both of these issues can be corrected by focusing on proper speaking, which forces a student to break down words into constituent parts and sound them out correctly.</p>
<h3>
5. Find a constructive teacher
</h3>

<p>   A <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0346251X13001905">recent paper</a> studies students&#39; journal entries to understand how teachers affect willingness to communicate (WTC) in a new language.
   The students were a group of 50 undergrads who were required to write focused essays on their classroom conversations.
   Students generally felt more comfortable speaking a language if the teachers were patient when waiting for answers, let the students choose conversation topics, and did not immediately correct problems.</p>
<p>   In contrast, when teachers did not show patience, the students became obsessed with mistakes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p> It is very unpleasant to hear the correct grammatical form or pronunciation when you are speaking in the classroom...I decided to speak when I am sure about the accuracy of sentence I&#39;m going to say.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>   The students with the strongest WTC viewed the teachers more like friendly partners who &quot;help you to deliver your message by providing explanations.&quot;
   Finding language learning partners (via a service like <a href="https://www.cambly.com/">Cambly</a>) and using software that provides this kind of feedback can be more effective than classroom language learning.</p>
<h3>
6. Seek explicit feedback
</h3>

<p>   Have you ever tried to learn something when a teacher simply repeats the correct answer?
   This can be frustrating, especially when trying to pick up something subtle like an unexpected sound or vocab word.</p>
   <iframe class="block-center" width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kTcRRaXV-fg?start=90" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>   Three researchers from New Zealand <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263106060141">studied this problem</a> with students learning the English past tense.
   Not surprisingly, simply repeating the correct answer when students make mistakes is ineffective.
   Students do a far better job learning the past tense rules when they are explicitly corrected (e.g. &quot;you need the <em>-ed</em> past tense ending here&quot;).</p>
<p>   Seek out this explicit feedback when learning a language.
   It&#39;s a much faster way to improve and retain new information.</p>
<h3>
7. Train your ear
</h3>

<p>   Pronunciation is the key to success for learning a new language.</p>
<p>   One of the most studied pronunciation topics is how English speakers learn the difference between the <em>l-</em> and <em>r-</em> sounds as in &quot;lock&quot; and &quot;rock&quot; or &quot;load&quot; and &quot;road&quot;.
   Researchers at Carnegie Mellon dove into this problem in a <a href="http://psych.stanford.edu/~jlm/papers/McCFiezMcCandliss02.pdf">2002 paper</a>.
   The researchers had Japanese adults listen to a recording of &quot;lock&quot; or &quot;rock&quot; at random and then select the sound they heard.
   Although their initial performance was poor, it increased to 80% accuracy when the subjects received immediate feedback on wrong answers.
   More importantly, these subjects became better at distinguishing other English words and speaking correctly after the training.</p>
<p>   My buddy <a href="http://www.andyjiang.com/">Andy Jiang</a> and I built <a href="https://noobgerman.com/">Noob German</a> based on this research.
   Noob German is a simple flash card trainer for anyone learning German.
   Each flash card plays a German sound and you are asked to select from two options.</p>
<p>   <img src="images/noob_german.gif" width="600px" class="block-center"></img></p>
<p>   This pronunciation training kick starts your German learning.  Check out <a href="https://noobgerman.com/">Noob German</a> and please let us know your thoughts <a href="https://twitter.com/noobgerman">@NoobGerman</a>.</p>
</div><div class="footer"><hr><small>Want to get in touch? <a href="https://twitter.com/gwintrob">Tweet</a> 
at me.</small></div></div></body></html>]]></description><link>http://gwintrob.com/articles/7-lessons-for-language-learners</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://gwintrob.com/articles/7-lessons-for-language-learners</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Wintrob]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How Segment is Changing the SaaS Marketplace]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html><html><head><title>How Segment is Changing the SaaS Marketplace</title><meta name="description" content="Gordon Wintrob's Personal Site"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="http://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Raleway:100,400,600"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/style.css"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/ss-gizmo.css"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/ss-social-circle.css"><script>!function(){var analytics=window.analytics=window.analytics||[];if(!analytics.initialize)if(analytics.invoked)window.console&&console.error&&console.error("Segment snippet included twice.");else{analytics.invoked=!0;analytics.methods=["trackSubmit","trackClick","trackLink","trackForm","pageview","identify","group","track","ready","alias","page","once","off","on"];analytics.factory=function(t){return function(){var e=Array.prototype.slice.call(arguments);e.unshift(t);analytics.push(e);return analytics}};for(var t=0;t<analytics.methods.length;t++){var e=analytics.methods[t];analytics[e]=analytics.factory(e)}analytics.load=function(t){var e=document.createElement("script");e.type="text/javascript";e.async=!0;e.src=("https:"===document.location.protocol?"https://":"http://")+"cdn.segment.com/analytics.js/v1/"+t+"/analytics.min.js";var n=document.getElementsByTagName("script")[0];n.parentNode.insertBefore(e,n)};analytics.SNIPPET_VERSION="3.0.1";
analytics.load("Boo2cBGyhUD4L9UEaLSQXJr2MMZWP7tu");
analytics.page()
}}();</script><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/c3/0.4.8/c3.min.css"></head><body><div class="nav"><a href="/" class="a-fade ss-gizmo ss-home a-home"></a></div><div class="header"><h1 class="name">Gordon Wintrob</h1><div class="social-links"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">linkedin</a><a href="https://twitter.com/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">twitter</a><a href="https://github.com/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">octocat</a><a href="/rss.xml" class="a-fade ss-icon">rss</a><a href="mailto:gwintrob@gmail.com?Subject=Hey Gordon" class="a-fade ss-icon">mail</a></div></div><div class="article"><h1 class="article-title">How Segment is Changing the SaaS Marketplace</h1><div class="article-contents"><p><a href="https://segment.com/">Segment</a> is a customer data hub that makes it easy for websites and mobile apps to integrate 3rd-party analytics tools.
With all the customer data already flowing through them, Segment is opening a powerful distribution channel for data-powered SaaS businesses.</p>
<p><img src="images/segment_integrations.png" class="img-segment-integrations"></img></p>
<p>Full disclosure &mdash; I&#39;m close with the Segment team and they were customers of my company <a href="https://stacklead.com/">StackLead</a>.
I think they&#39;re poised to win with:
an <a href="http://www.forbes.com/pictures/mll45kfhf/calvin-french-owen-25-ian-storm-taylor-25-llya-volodarsky-24-peter-reinhardt-25/">incredible team</a> with <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/benkepes/2014/10/08/segment-raises-15m-for-a-customer-data-hub/">serious fundraising</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/segmentio/analytics.js">huge</a> <a href="https://github.com/segmentio/myth">open-source</a> <a href="https://github.com/segmentio/nightmare">contributions</a>,
and a number of important enterprise customers like Nokia and Live Nation.
Everything in this post uses public data.</p>
<h3 id="crawling-for-customer-trackers">Crawling for Customer Trackers</h3>
<p>I analyzed the <a href="https://info.crunchbase.com/about/crunchbase-data-exports/">Crunchbase Data Export</a> from December 2, 2014.
First, I filtered this data down to the 20,186 companies that have raised more than $1m USD in funding and are still operating.
Then, I crawled all of the company websites to identify the SaaS trackers they had installed.&nbsp;[1]</p>
<p>Across this set of companies, there were 895 distinct trackers (e.g.&nbsp;analytics tools, web bugs, and ad pixels) and each company used <strong>3&nbsp;trackers</strong> on average.
Traditionally, installing each of these trackers is painful, error-prone work that&#39;s pretty boring for programmers.
The Segment platform suddenly makes it possible to integrate precise tools for parts of sales, marketing, customer success, etc. without wasting valuable engineering time.</p>
<h3 id="the-tracking-landscape">The Tracking Landscape</h3>
<p>First, I looked at the number of companies that installed each of the top 10 data trackers, along with the percentage of those companies that also integrated Segment.
The top trackers are mostly free tools, so they scale for consumer products that are less likely than B2B companies to need customer-level tracking.</p>
<div id="popular-chart1" class="chart">
</div>

<p>Google Analytics dominates &mdash; nearly 13,000 companies (63% of the dataset) use the popular service, but only 224 companies in this group (2%) are also Segment customers.</p>
<p>The next 10 most popular trackers include a number of paid analytics and marketing automation products.</p>
<div id="popular-chart2" class="chart">
</div>

<p>Datapoints that jump out:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Marketo and Pardot</strong>: Only 2% of Marketo customers and 1% of Pardot customers also use Segment.
Companies that use these services are willing to pay a premium and Segment&#39;s biggest opportunity is selling into large enterprises with big integration issues.</li>
<li><strong>Mixpanel, Olark, and KISSmetrics</strong>: These are approachable tools that lots of startups love.
Segment has a solid 12-17% penetration with their customer base.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="drilling-down-by-funding">Drilling down by Funding</h3>
<p>Segment has the greatest penetration with earlier-stage companies ($1&#8209;3mm in funding) and obviously has a big opportunity to move upmarket.
Also, as these smaller companies grow, Segment is well-positioned to cater to their expanding customer data needs.</p>
<div id="funding-chart" class="chart">
</div>

<h3 id="drilling-down-by-market">Drilling down by Market</h3>
<p>The next chart shows data for the top 10 markets, sorted based on the average number of trackers used by the companies in each market.</p>
<div id="market-chart" class="chart">
</div>

<p>We see an interesting correlation: as the number of trackers per company decreases (from 6.1 for the average e-commerce website to 1.0 for biotech), Segment&#39;s penetration in the market also goes down.
Segment is increasingly valuable for industries that spend engineering effort on implementing trackers.
Importantly, these are high-growth industries like e-commerce and enterprise software that are looking to adopt new SaaS solutions.</p>
<h3 id="how-segment-is-changing-the-saas-marketplace">How Segment is Changing the SaaS Marketplace</h3>
<p>Segment&#39;s biggest impact is unprecedented distribution for new analytics tools and trackers.
For companies like <a href="http://customer.io/">Customer.io</a> and <a href="https://amplitude.com/">Amplitude</a>, 2/3 of their customers are also Segment users.
Here are the trackers with the highest percentage of customers using Segment:</p>
<div id="changing-chart" class="chart">
</div>

<p>Previously, integration pains were a huge barrier for new SaaS products to gain traction.
Segment is well-positioned to solve this problem and make it extremely easy for businesses (from startups to large enterprises) to mix and match their ideal customer data setup.</p>
<p>[1] You can use a tool like <a href="https://www.ghostery.com">Ghostery</a> to manually view the trackers on a site you&#39;re browsing.</p>
</div><div class="footer"><hr><small>Want to get in touch? <a href="https://twitter.com/gwintrob">Tweet</a> 
at me.</small></div></div><script type="text/javascript" src="http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.11.2/jquery.min.js"></script><script type="text/javascript" src="http://d3js.org/d3.v3.min.js"></script><script type="text/javascript" src="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/c3/0.4.8/c3.min.js"></script><script type="text/javascript" src="data/aggregate_data.js"></script><script type="text/javascript" src="javascripts/segment_data.js"></script></body></html>]]></description><link>http://gwintrob.com/articles/how-segment-is-changing-the-saas-marketplace</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://gwintrob.com/articles/how-segment-is-changing-the-saas-marketplace</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Wintrob]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2015 Resolutions]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html><html><head><title>2015 Resolutions</title><meta name="description" content="Gordon Wintrob's Personal Site"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="http://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Raleway:100,400,600"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/style.css"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/ss-gizmo.css"><link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="css/ss-social-circle.css"><script>!function(){var analytics=window.analytics=window.analytics||[];if(!analytics.initialize)if(analytics.invoked)window.console&&console.error&&console.error("Segment snippet included twice.");else{analytics.invoked=!0;analytics.methods=["trackSubmit","trackClick","trackLink","trackForm","pageview","identify","group","track","ready","alias","page","once","off","on"];analytics.factory=function(t){return function(){var e=Array.prototype.slice.call(arguments);e.unshift(t);analytics.push(e);return analytics}};for(var t=0;t<analytics.methods.length;t++){var e=analytics.methods[t];analytics[e]=analytics.factory(e)}analytics.load=function(t){var e=document.createElement("script");e.type="text/javascript";e.async=!0;e.src=("https:"===document.location.protocol?"https://":"http://")+"cdn.segment.com/analytics.js/v1/"+t+"/analytics.min.js";var n=document.getElementsByTagName("script")[0];n.parentNode.insertBefore(e,n)};analytics.SNIPPET_VERSION="3.0.1";
analytics.load("Boo2cBGyhUD4L9UEaLSQXJr2MMZWP7tu");
analytics.page()
}}();</script></head><body><div class="nav"><a href="/" class="a-fade ss-gizmo ss-home a-home"></a></div><div class="header"><h1 class="name">Gordon Wintrob</h1><div class="social-links"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">linkedin</a><a href="https://twitter.com/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">twitter</a><a href="https://github.com/gwintrob" class="a-fade ss-icon">octocat</a><a href="/rss.xml" class="a-fade ss-icon">rss</a><a href="mailto:gwintrob@gmail.com?Subject=Hey Gordon" class="a-fade ss-icon">mail</a></div></div><div class="article"><h1 class="article-title">2015 Resolutions</h1><div class="article-contents"><p>Rather than write down New Year&#39;s resolutions, I tend to think of general areas to improve over the following year.
Unfortunately, I&#39;m left without any concrete, measurable improvements, so I&#39;m going to take a different approach for 2015.
Here are two specific resolutions I&#39;m gunning for over the next 12 months.</p>
<ol>
<li><p>Anf&auml;nger Deutsch</p>
<p>For the past two months, I&#39;ve been learning German via <a href="https://www.duolingo.com/gwintrob">Duolingo</a> and <a href="http://www.memrise.com/user/gordonw/">Memrise</a>.
I currently know roughly 500 words and I&#39;ll write more about my motivation and techniques in a future post.
My overall goal is to become a competent beginner German speaker by the end of 2015.</p>
<p>For a concrete task, I commit to learning 125 words per month, which means I&#39;ll be on the same level as a Kindergarten student according to <a href="http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2005-03588-011">this paper</a>.
By the way, German &quot;die Kinder&quot; means &quot;the children&quot;.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Create More</p>
<p>It feels so good to binge watch House of Cards, read good novels, and plow through Twitter.
<a href="https://twitter.com/mikaelcho">Mikael Cho</a> provides a good summary <a href="https://medium.com/@mikaelcho/create-more-than-you-consume-9c1bc89dc71d">here</a>.
As a software engineer, I&#39;m lucky that my biggest hobby is also my line of work <em>and</em> it&#39;s a hobby with easily-shared output.</p>
<p>To deliver on this goal, I&#39;m going to write at least one article here each month for the next 12 months.
I have a backlog of posts on startups, data science, and half-baked side projects.
Committing to monthly writing will force me to put pen to paper with these ideas.
If I have nothing to say for a month, then I know I&#39;m not following through on this goal.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Also, thanks to design inspiration from my roommate <a href="http://ianstormtaylor.com/">Ian Storm Taylor</a> and his open source <a href="http://www.metalsmith.io/">Metalsmith</a> for powering this blog.
Lots of improvements to make to the site :-)
Enjoy the New Year&#39;s Eve celebrations!</p>
</div><div class="footer"><hr><small>Want to get in touch? <a href="https://twitter.com/gwintrob">Tweet</a> 
at me.</small></div></div></body></html>]]></description><link>http://gwintrob.com/articles/2015-resolutions</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://gwintrob.com/articles/2015-resolutions</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Gordon Wintrob]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>